=Romance of a Twin Flower=
= Romance de una flor gemela =
=Episode 16=
= Episodio 16 =
(Jiangzhen Pavilion)
(Pabellón Jiangzhen)
Sangyu.
Sangyu.
I thought that...
Pensé que
I thought they would forget
pensé que olvidarían
the title of She-devil
el título de She-devil
after I left the capital,
después de salir de la capital,
and I could start over.
y podría volver a empezar.
But Lianxiang is right.
Pero Lianxiang tiene razón.
Those I hurt
Aquellos que lastimo
will never forget
nunca olvidaré
how I hurt them.
cómo les hice daño.
They will never forget
Nunca olvidarán
the mistakes I made.
los errores que cometí.
It's not your fault.
No es tu culpa.
Whose fault is that then?
¿De quién es entonces?
In fact...
De hecho,
I don't need comfort,
no necesito consuelo,
because I don't deserve it.
porque no lo merezco.
I...
Yo...
I have something to tell you.
Tengo algo que decirte.
I am begging you.
Te ruego.
Could you
¿Podría
leave me alone?
déjame en paz?
Okay.
Está bien.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Sangyu.
Sangyu.
What's up?
¿Qué pasa?
Qingyun.
Qingyun.
What's wrong with your foot?
¿Qué pasa con tu pie?
I...
Yo...
I am fine.
Estoy bien.
I sprained my ankle on the way.
Me extendí el tobillo en el camino.
Where is my sister?
¿Dónde está mi hermana?
Sangyu.
Sangyu.
Be careful.
Ten cuidado.
Brother-in-law.
Cuñado.
Where is my sister?
¿Dónde está mi hermana?
What happened today?
¿Qué pasó hoy?
Yuxuan.
Yuxuan.
How is Her Ladyship now?
¿Cómo está Su señoría ahora?
Ning Yuxuan, say something.
Ning Yuxuan, di algo.
How is she now?
¿Cómo es ella ahora?
It's all my fault.
Es todo mi culpa.
I couldn't go to the trade fair
No podía ir a la feria
after I sprained my ankle.
después de dilatarme el tobillo.
Or they wouldn't be able to
O no podrían
bully my sister.
intimidan a mi hermana.
I'm going to see her.
Voy a verla.
Don't go.
No te vayas.
She said
Ella dijo que
she wanted to be alone for a while.
quería estar sola por un tiempo.
- But... - Qingyun.
- Pero... - Qingyun.
Come and take a seat.
Ven a tomar asiento.
Yuxuan.
Yuxuan.
Don't you think something is wrong?
¿No crees que algo está mal?
What happened to Lianxiang...
¿Qué le pasó a Lianxiang...
How could it be such a coincidence?
¿Cómo podría ser una coincidencia así?
What do you mean?
¿Qué quieres decir?
Three years ago,
Hace tres años,
we gave Lianxiang
le dimos a Lianxiang
a hundred taels to let her leave the Mansion.
cien taels para dejarla salir de la mansión.
But why did she say
Pero, ¿por qué dijo
she was sold to a brothel?
se le vendió a un burdel?
Why do you remember it so clearly?
¿Por qué lo recuerdas tan claramente?
I have been in charge of the accounts of the Marquis's Mansion.
He estado a cargo de las cuentas de la mansión del Marqués.
I have an impression of this.
Tengo una impresión de esto.
So what happened tonight was no coincidence.
Así que lo que pasó esta noche no fue ninguna coincidencia.
Someone ordered her to come back?
¿Alguien le ordenó volver?
Of course she was ordered.
Claro que se le ordenó.
Here, take some water.
Aquí, toma un poco de agua.
This is where you live
Aquí es donde vives
from now on.
a partir de ahora.
I'll live next door to you.
Voy a vivir al lado de ti.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
You are so nice to me.
Eres tan amable conmigo.
Will you blame me
¿Me culparías
for my gaffe today?
por mi metida de pata hoy?
I didn't expect
No esperaba
Nie Sangyu
nie Sangyu
to be so vicious.
ser tan vicioso.
But don't worry.
Pero no te preocupes.
I will be on your side.
Estaré de tu parte.
If you
Si tú
had told me
me lo había dicho
these things earlier,
estas cosas antes,
how could you have suffered?
cómo has podido sufrir?
But Miss Shui, I was afraid.
Pero señorita Shui, tenía miedo.
I was even more frightened
Me asusté aún más
when I saw her.
cuando la vi.
As soon as I close my eyes,
En cuanto cierre mis ojos,
I can see her beating me
puedo verla golpeándome
with a whip in my mind,
con un látigo en mi mente,
injuring me so badly.
me hiere tanto.
She is the general's daughter
Ella es la hija del general
and the marquis's wife,
y la esposa del marqués,
but I am just
pero solo soy
an orphan.
huérfano.
I am worse than
Soy peor que
an ant to her.
como hormiga para ella.
I brought shame on her
Le traje vergüenza
on impulse this time.
bajo impulso esta vez.
She will never let me go.
Nunca me dejará ir.
So what if she is noble?
¿Y si es noble?
We are no longer the weak girls
Ya no somos las chicas débiles
who let others bully us.
que permitieron que otros nos intimidaran.
Lianxiang, remember.
Lianxiang, recuerda.
You are now a member of Shuiyan House.
Ahora es miembro de la Casa Shuiyan.
I will be responsible to you.
Seré responsable contigo.
I will do my best
Haré todo lo que esté en mi mano
to protect you.
para protegerte.
Trust me, okay?
Confía en mí, ¿de acuerdo?
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Take a good rest.
Descansa bien.
Stop crying.
Deja de llorar.
Your Lordship.
Su señoría.
How is Sangyu?
¿Qué tal Sangyu?
She still doesn't eat or drink,
Todavía no come ni bebe,
and is shutting herself in the room,
y se enciende en la habitación,
not letting others in.
no dejar entrar a otros.
It's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
I shouldn't have hidden it from her.
No debería haberla ocultado.
Otherwise, she wouldn't be in such pain.
De lo contrario, no sufriría tanto dolor.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
Your Lordship.Your Lordship.
Su señoría.Su señorío.
Haoxue Cosmetics has been smashed.
Los cosméticos de Haoxue han sido destruidos.
Her Ladyship rushed out
Su señoría salió corriendo
after hearing the news.
después de escuchar la noticia.
What?
¿Qué?
Why didn't you stop her?
¿Por qué no la dejaste?
I...
Yo...
Your...
Tu...
Stop it.
Detente.
How did your hand get hurt?
¿Cómo te dolió la mano?
Do you remember
¿Recuerdas
when it
cuando
first opened?
la primera apertura?
At that time, I really thought
En ese momento, realmente pensé que
my dream had come true.
mi sueño se había hecho realidad.
Now it's all gone.
Ahora todo se ha ido.
Tell me.
Dime.
How can I be so vicious?
¿Cómo puedo ser tan vicioso?
How many bad things have I done?
¿Cuántas malas cosas he hecho?
How many bad things have I done
¿Cuántas cosas malas que hice
that I don't know yet?
que todavía no sé?
It's not your fault.
No es tu culpa.
The She-devil left the capital,
El diablo dejó la capital,
and is still a She-devil
y sigue siendo un Diablo
after being chased to Haifang.
después de ser expulsado a Haifang.
I can't get rid of it.
No puedo deshacerme de ello.
No matter where I am,
Sin importar donde esté,
no matter what I do,
no importa lo que haga,
no one will believe me.
nadie me creerá.
No one will believe me.
Nadie me creerá.
None of this is your fault.
Nada de esto es tu culpa.
It's Nie Sangyu's fault.
Es culpa de Nie Sangyu.
It's Nie Sangyu.
Es Nie Sangyu.
Although you look exactly
Aunque ves exactamente
the same as Nie Sangyu,
el mismo que Nie Sangyu,
you two have very different personalities,
ustedes dos tienen personalidades muy diferentes,
and are not the same person at all.
y no son la misma persona en absoluto.
The real Nie Sangyu
La Nie Sangyu real
has the imprint of plum blossoms on her shoulder,
tiene la impronta de flores de ciruelo en su hombro,
but you don't.
pero tú no.
(I don't care if you're playing the fool)
(No me importa si estás jugando al ridículo)
(Reflection Pavilion) (or you've really lost your memory.)
(Pabellón de reflejo) (o realmente has perdido la memoria.)
(What's done is done.)
(Lo que se ha hecho está hecho.)
You can't deny it.
No se puede negar.
(Couldn't I do this before?)
(¿No podía hacerlo antes?)
No.
No.
Did I know how to cook before?
¿Sé cocinar antes?
You didn't even know
Ni siquiera sabían que
where the kitchen is.
dónde está la cocina.
(Let me go.)
(Déjame ir.)
Let me go.
Déjame ir.
I've told you
Te lo he dicho
many times that
muchas veces que
we're not a perfect match.
no somos una pareja perfecta.
Stop forcing me, okay?
Deja de forzarme, ¿de acuerdo?
Then why did you
Entonces, ¿por qué
try so hard
intenta tanto
to marry me before?
casarse conmigo antes?
(So did something else)
(Entonces hizo algo más)
(pop out)
(salir)
(of your mind?)
(de tu mente?)
Something else?
¿Otra cosa?
For example,
Por ejemplo,
memories from the past.
recuerdos del pasado.
(Haoxue Cosmetics Shop is opening now.)
(La tienda de cosméticos Haoxue comienza ahora.)
(Ms. Nie,)
(Sra. Nie,)
(may your shop prosper in the years to come,)
(Que su tienda prospere en los años venideros,)
(and may it get you lots of fortune.)
(y que te aporte mucha fortuna.)
(Wishing you prosperity and all the best.)
(Te deseo prosperidad y lo mejor.)
(Those I hurt)
(Aquellos que lastimo)
(will never forget)
(nunca olvidaré)
(how I hurt them.)
(cómo los lastimé.)
They will never forget
Nunca olvidarán
the mistakes I made.
los errores que cometí.
It's not your fault.
No es tu culpa.
Whose fault is that then?
¿De quién es entonces?
I... I am not Nie Sangyu?
Yo... No soy Nie Sangyu?
Then who am I?
Entonces, ¿quién soy?
Your name is Ji Man,
Tu nombre es Ji Man,
and you should be the daughter of Guihai Warrior.
y deberías ser la hija de Guihai Warrior.
How do you know?
¿Cómo lo sabes?
At that time, Shen Liancheng robbed Ship Guihai.
En esa época, Shen Liancheng ladrón Guihai.
I found a formula
Encontré una fórmula
(for Scar Recovering Cream)
para Scar Recovering Cream
(signed by Ji Man on the boat,)
firmado por Ji Man en el barco,
(Formula for Scar Recovering Cream) (which is exactly the same as yours.)
(Fórmula para Scar Recovering Cream) que es exactamente el mismo que el tuyo.
(Wang Ba) (And the connected words)
(Wang Ba) Y las palabras relacionadas
are the same as the ones you gave me back then.
son las mismas que las me diste en ese momento.
It must be you.
Debe ser tú.
You are not Nie Sangyu.
No eres Nie Sangyu.
You are Ji Man.
Eres Ji Man.
That's to say...
Eso es para decir
That's to say,
es decir,
I'm really not Nie Sangyu.
realmente no soy Nie Sangyu.
So
Así
none of these bad things were done by me.
ninguna de estas malas cosas lo hice yo.
And
Y
I didn't hurt those people,
no lastimé a esa gente,
did I?
yo?
You didn't.
Usted no lo hizo.
Am I really not Nie Sangyu?
¿En realidad no soy Nie Sangyu?
You are not Nie Sangyu.
No eres Nie Sangyu.
I'm not Nie Sangyu.
No soy Nie Sangyu.
I'm going to tell them.
Voy a decirles.
I am going to tell everyone
Voy a decirle a todos
that I am not Nie Sangyu.
que no soy Nie Sangyu.
When did you know this?
¿Cuándo sabías esto?
I...
Yo...
Back then, there were many doubts,
En aquel entonces, había muchas dudas,
and I finally
y finalmente
confirmed it
lo confirmé
after several investigations.
después de varias investigaciones.
I...
Yo...
So you knew this
¿Entonces sabías esto
when the fair was held?
cuando se llevó a cabo la feria?
I was going to
Iba a
tell you later, but...
se lo dije más tarde, pero...
It's my fault.
Es mi culpa.
None of this would have happened
Nada de esto habría sucedido
if I had told you earlier.
si te lo hubiera dicho antes.
I am willing to make it up.
Estoy dispuesto a compensarlo.
How can you make it up?
¿Cómo puedes inventarlo?
Since you knew that
Ya que sabes que
I am not Nie Sangyu long ago,
no soy Nie Sangyu hace mucho tiempo,
why didn't you tell me earlier?
por qué no me lo dijiste antes?
Everyone thinks
Todos creen que
I'm the one who did the bad thing.
yo soy quien hizo lo malo.
No one will believe that I am not her.
Nadie creerá que No soy ella.
No one will believe that
Nadie creerá que
I didn't do any of them.
no hice ninguno de ellos.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
¿Por qué no me lo dijiste antes?
If I could justify myself,
Si pudiera justificarse,
my Haoxue Cosmetics wouldn't have been smashed.
mis cosméticos de Haoxue no se habría roto.
Tell me how to make it up.
Dime cómo compensarlo.
I...
Yo...
Leave.
Déjate.
I don't want to see you.
No te quiero ver.
Ji Man.
Ji Man.
Leave!
¡Deja!
Okay.
Está bien.
♪Whisper your name for me♪
♪ Duele tu nombre para mí ♪
♪The scenery floating in the sea of people♪
♪ El escenario flotante en el mar de gente ♪
♪I can't catch up with your back♪
♪ No puedo alcanzarte la espalda ♪
♪How long have we been looking at each other♪
♪ Durante cuánto tiempo hemos estado mirándonos mutuamente ♪
♪To live up to the fate♪
♪ Viva el destino ♪
♪I'm afraid we're never destined♪
♪ Me temo que nunca estamos destinados ♪
♪Even breathing becomes lighter♪
♪ Aún la respiración se vuelve más ligera ♪
♪Finally stop crying♪
♪ Por último, deja de llorar ♪
♪As time goes by♪
♪ A medida que pasa el tiempo ♪
♪Seeing you through♪
♪ Visto a través de ♪
♪You are the reflected star♪
♪ Tú eres la estrella reflejada ♪
♪An unattainable shadow♪
♪ Una sombra inalcanzable ♪
♪Touching you broke the fate♪
♪ Tocándote rompió el destino ♪
♪I am the floating cloud♪
♪ Yo soy la nube flotante ♪
♪Please forget my name♪
♪ Por favor olvídense de mi nombre ♪
♪There will be sunshine after the storm♪
♪ Habrá sol después de la tormenta ♪
Follow us.
Síguenos.
You idiot.
Idiota.
You screwed things up over and over again.
Arruinaste las cosas una y otra vez.
Not only was the tax money lost,
No solo se perdió el dinero de los impuestos,
but the Dragon Gang was about to disperse.
pero la Banda de Dragón estaba a punto de dispersarse.
Are you trying to
¿Estás tratando de
court death?
muerte en los tribunales?
My bad.
Mi mal.
But Ning Yuxuan
Pero Ning Yuxuan
is indeed powerful.
es verdaderamente poderoso.
Thank you for your rescue, sir.
Gracias por su rescate, señor.
Please give me another chance.
Por favor, dame otra oportunidad.
I will kill Ning Yuxuan myself.
Mataré a Ning Yuxuan yo mismo.
Okay.
Está bien.
I will give you another chance.
Te daré otra oportunidad.
(Everyone thinks)
(Todos piensan que)
(I'm the one who did the bad thing.)
(Soy el que hizo lo malo.)
(No one will believe that I am not her.)
(Nadie creerá que No soy ella.)
(No one will believe that.)
(Nadie lo creerá.)
(Haoxue Cosmetics shouldn't have been smashed.)
(Los cosméticos de Haoxue no deberían se han roto.)
(Tell me how to make it up.)
(Dime cómo inventarlo.)
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
We got the news that
Recibimos la noticia de que
Shen Liancheng disappeared
desapareció Shen Liancheng
after being taken away by mysterious men.
después de ser quitado por hombres misteriosos.
I see.
Veo.
Over the past few days,
En los últimos días,
your chess skills
tus habilidades de ajedrez
have improved a lot.
ha mejorado mucho.
I am flattered.
Me estás alabando en exceso.
I'm just a student
Solo soy un estudiante
compared to you.
comparado con usted.
I heard that
Escuché que
Ning Yuxuan is living
ning Yuxuan está viviendo
a happy life in Haifang.
una vida feliz en Haifang.
The way to play chess is
La manera de jugar al ajedrez es
to command the overall situation.
dirigir la situación general.
Take the butterfly effect into consideration.
Tome el efecto mariposa en consideración.
Avoid ignoring details
Evita ignorar detalles
and being taken advantage of.
y ser aprovechado.
What's your
¿Cuál es tu
next step?
el siguiente paso?
Things are like chess.
Las cosas son como el ajedrez.
Turning the tide lies in this crucial step.
Cambiar la marea yace en este paso crucial.
A risky move breaks the game.
Un movimiento riesgoso rompe el juego.
Looks like you've
Parece que has
planned and prepared the game.
planeado y preparado el juego.
In my opinion,
En mi opinión,
the game
el juego
has just started.
acaba de empezar.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
A murder case occurred in Shuiyan House.
Ocurrió un caso de asesinato en la Casa Shuiyan.
Lianxiang was assassinated
Lianxiang fue asesinada
in her room last night.
anoche en su habitación.
Lianxiang was assassinated?
¿Lianxiang fue asesinada?
Yes.
Sí.
What's the situation at the scene?
¿Cuál es la situación en el escenario?
Mr. Liu and Mr. Li
Sr. Liu y Sr. Li
have gone to the scene
han ido a la escena
and found Her Ladyship's jade pendant
y encontró a su señoría colgante de jade
in Lianxiang's room.
en la habitación de Lianxiang.
What?
¿Qué?
(Shuiyan House)
(Shuiyan House)
Sir.
Señor.
This jade pendant can be used as physical evidence.
Este colgante de jade puede utilizarse como evidencia física.
Was it found in this room?
¿Se encontró en esta habitación?
Yes.
Sí.
You've asked everyone?
¿Le has preguntado a todos?
Right.
Cierto.
Everyone said that
Todos dijeron que
this physical evidence is true.
esta evidencia física es cierta.
I see.
Ya veo.
Mr. Ning.
Sr. Ning.
You came just in time.
Viniste justo a tiempo.
As identified by many maids of Haoxue Cosmetics,
Identificado por muchas criadas de los cosméticos de Haoxue,
the jade pendant found in the room of the deceased
el colgante de jade encontrado en la habitación del fallecido
was the same one worn
era la misma usada
by Her Lordship Nie Sangyu
por Su Señoría Nie Sangyu
during the banquet
durante el banquete
at Shuiyan House
en la Casa Shuiyan
last night.
anoche.
It does belong to my wife.
Pertenece a mi esposa.
But one object alone
Pero un objeto solo
is not enough to convict her.
no es suficiente para condenarla.
Not enough?
¿No es suficiente?
Mr. Ning.
Sr. Ning.
This jade pendant
Este colgante de jade
is obviously something precious.
es obviamente algo precioso.
Mrs. Ning must wear it every day
La Sra. Ning debe usarlo todos los días
and keep it carefully.
y guardarlo con cuidado.
Now it appeared at the scene of the crime,
Ahora apareció en el lugar del crimen,
which can be described as conclusive evidence.
que puede describirse como prueba concluyente.
Mr. Ning,
Sr. Ning,
are you trying to call white black?
estás tratando de llamar blanco negro?
Mr. Wang.
Sr. Wang.
What a coincidence.
Qué coincidencia.
Why are you here
¿Por qué estás aquí
all of a sudden?
de repente?
The matter
El asunto
has something to do with the Sea Trade Guild's reputation.
tiene algo que ver con la reputación de la Asociación de Comercio Marítimo.
Of course we are very concerned.
Claro que estamos muy preocupados.
Nie Sangyu
Nie Sangyu
is not only Mr. Ning's wife,
no es solo la esposa del Sr. Ning,
but also a lady with imperial mandate.
sino también una dama con mandato imperial.
Now she's committed a murder.
Ahora ha cometido un asesinato.
As the magistrate,
Como juez,
Mr. Ning,
sr. Ning,
please enforce the law impartially,
haga cumplir la ley imparcialmente,
return justice to the deceased
devuelva justicia al fallecido
and return dignity to the law.
y devolver la dignidad a la ley.
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
Convey my order.
Transmite mi orden.
Arrest the suspect
Arresta al sospechoso
Nie Sangyu immediately.
nie Sangyu inmediatamente.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Let me go.
Déjame ir.
Why are you arresting me?
¿Por qué me arrestas?
Help!
¡Ayuda!
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Sir.
Señor.
Open the door.
Abre la puerta.
Yes.
Sí.
Mr. Qin.
Sr. Qin.
- What happened? - Hush.
- ¿Qué pasó? - Espera.
Lianxiang was assassinated
Lianxiang fue asesinado en Shuiyan House
at Shuiyan House last night.
anoche.
What?
¿Qué?
How is she now?
¿Cómo es ahora?
She succumbed to the injury.
Ella sucumbió a la lesión.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Take a seat.
Tome asiento.
I see.
Veo.
Because of what happened in Shuiyan House yesterday,
Por lo que pasó en Shuiyan House ayer,
I am now
ahora soy
the prime suspect.
el principal sospechoso.
The most serious thing is that
Lo más serio es que
your jade pendant was found
se encontró tu colgante de jade
at the scene where Lianxiang was murdered.
en la escena donde Lianxiang es asesinado.
The jade pendant...
El colgante de jade...
They must have stolen it
Deben haberla robado
and tried to frame me.
e intentaron incriminarme.
Right.
Derecho.
Your Ladyship.
Su señoría.
Where did you go after
¿A dónde fuiste tras
you left Shuiyan House last night? Any witnesses?
dejaste Shuiyan House anoche? ¿Testigos?
Last night...
Anoche...
Last night
Anoche
I had been staying in Haoxue Cosmetics
me había estado quedando en cosméticos Haoxue
and never left.
y nunca se fue.
But the only witness
Pero el único testigo
is Ning Yuxuan.
es Ning Yuxuan.
Given our relationship,
Dada nuestra relación,
this is simply not enough evidence.
sencillamente, no es suficiente evidencia.
Mr. Qin.
Sr. Qin.
They must have targeted me
Deben haberme dirigido
about this.
sobre esto.
So
Entonces, Lianxiang estuvo implicado por mí.
Lianxiang was implicated by me.
Lianxiang estuvo implicado por mí.
Find out the murderer as soon as possible,
Averigua al asesino lo antes posible,
and don't let her die in vain.
y no la dejes morir en vano.
Your Ladyship, don't worry.
Su señoría, no te preocupes.
Mr. Ning is on it.
El Sr. Ning está en ello.
He will definitely find out the truth.
Definitivamente descubrirá la verdad.
These days, you may have to stay here.
Estos días, es posible que tengas que quedarte aquí.
Take care of yourself.
Cuídate.
I have to go.
Tengo que ir.
Okay.
Está bien.
(Shuiyan House)
(Shuiyan House)
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
I have some questions
Tengo algunas preguntas
for you about
para ti
what happened to my wife.
qué pasó con mi esposa.
I know very little.
Sé muy poco.
I can't tell you much.
No te puedo decir mucho.
You were the first to discover that
Fuiste el primero en descubrir que
Lianxiang was killed this morning.
lianxiang murió esta mañana.
Yes.
Sí.
She had been dead for a long time
Había muerto durante mucho tiempo
when I found her.
cuando la encontré.
And there was no trace of a fight
Y no había rastro de una pelea
at the scene.
en el lugar.
Then I notified the local government.
Luego le notificé al gobierno local.
They found your wife's
Encontraron a tu esposa
jade pendant right there.
colgante de jade allí.
Anything else?
¿Algo más?
Please think carefully
Por favor, piénsalo bien
if there is anything strange.
si hay algo extraño.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
You have had contact
Has tenido contacto
with my wife.
con mi esposa.
You know her
Conoces a ella
better than anyone.
mejor que nadie.
The current situation is against her.
La situación actual es contra ella.
Your words
Tus palabras
are very important to us
para nosotros es muy importante
if we are to prove her innocence.
si vamos a demostrar su inocencia.
Since you knew she was wronged,
Ya que sabes que fue agraviada,
why did you
por qué
put her in the cell?
ponerla en la celda?
I...
Yo...
Of course I have my reasons
Claro que tengo mis razones
for doing this.
por hacer esto.
That's all I know.
Eso es todo lo que sé.
If there is nothing else,
Si no hay nada más,
please go back.
vuelve, por favor.
Gui Bai.
Gui Bai.
What do you think of this?
¿Qué piensas de esto?
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
I don't understand.
No entiendo.
Now that Her Ladyship is innocent,
Ahora que su señoría es inocente,
why were you in such a hurry
por qué tuviste tanta prisa
to put her in prison?
ponerla en prisión?
She's a titled lady.
Es una dama con título.
And it involves murder.
Y esto implica asesinato.
If this matter is reported to the capital,
Si se informa de este asunto a la capital,
it will definitely alarm those of the Court of Judicial Review.
definitivamente alarmará a aquellos del Tribunal de Revisión Judicial.
It's the best way
Es la mejor manera
I can think of
puedo pensar en
now.
ahora.
It's just that I can't
Es solo que no puedo
explain it to others.
explicar a los demás.
Now I understand
Ahora entiendo
your difficulties.
tus dificultades.
What do you think of
¿Qué piensas de
the words of Miss Shui?
las palabras de la señorita Shui?
I don't think
No creo que
Miss Shui told the full story.
la señorita Shui contó toda la historia.
And she seems to be afraid and hiding something.
Y parece tener miedo y ocultar algo.
It seems she doesn't trust me.
Parece que no confía en mí.
Well,
Bueno,
follow her these days.
seguidla estos días.
Report to me in time
Infórmelo a tiempo
if anything happens.
si pasa algo.
Yes, sir.
Sí, señor.
Your Lordship.
Su Señoría.
- Your Lordship.
- Su Señoría.
Leave us alone.
Déjanos solos.
- Yes, sir.
- Sí, señor.
I don't want to see you.
No te quiero ver.
Why are you here?
¿Por qué estás aquí?
Eat something.
Come algo.
Health goes first.
La salud es lo primero.
What about Lianxiang?
¿Y Lianxiang?
After the forensic doctor finishes the autopsy,
Después de que el médico forense finaliza la autopsia,
I will ask someone to arrange her funeral.
pediré a alguien para arreglar su funeral.
Can you eat now?
¿Puede comer ahora?
I brought your favorite roast chicken,
Traje tu pollo asado favorito,
pancakes,
pasteles,
and
y
trotters.
trompetas.
I have also brought
También he traído
your pillow
su almohada
and bedding.
y ropa de cama.
Am I going to live here for a long time?
¿Voy a vivir aquí durante mucho tiempo?
It's complicated.
Es complicado.
My wife.
Mi esposa.
Don't call me that.
No me llames así.
I'm not your wife at all.
No soy tu esposa en absoluto.
We have nothing to do
No tenemos nada que hacer
with each other now.
con el otro ahora.
Mr. Ning, hurry up and find out
Sr. Ning, date prisa y averigua
the real culprit who killed Lianxiang.
el culpable real que mató a Lianxiang.
Okay.
Está bien.
Eat something first.
Come algo primero.
I don't want to eat.
No quiero comer.
With you here,
Contigo aquí,
I have no appetite at all.
no tengo apetito en absoluto.
Get out.
Sal.
I...
Yo...
Leave!
¡Deja!
If you want to eat anything,
Si quieres comer algo,
tell the jailer.
dile al carcelero.
I'll prepare for you.
Me prepararé para ti.
Ning Yuxuan.
N Yuxuan.
The death of Lianxiang
La muerte de Lianxiang
remains unsolved.
sigue sin resolver.
But after all,
Pero después de todo,
she died because of me.
murió a causa de mí.
So please
Así que, por favor
find out the real culprit,
descubre al verdadero culpable,
uphold justice for her,
defiende justicia para ella,
and give her an explanation.
y darle una explicación.
I promise I will.
Prometo que lo haré.
Boss.
Jefe.
How is it going?
¿Cómo va?
Any updates?
¿Alguna actualización?
We made secret inquiries
Hicimos averiguaciones secretas
from all the merchants around Shuiyan House.
de todos los comerciantes alrededor de la Casa Shuiyan.
They said
Dijeron que
they didn't see anyone suspicious
no vieron a nadie sospechoso
that night.
esa noche.
You only checked the merchants?
¿Solo revisaste a los comerciantes?
Since the other party came prepared,
Como la otra parte vino preparada,
how could that person
cómo pudo esa persona
swagger in?
nadador?
Keep digging.
Sigue cavando.
Check all the people
Revisa a toda la gente
who passed by Shuiyan House
que pasó por Shuiyan House
that night.
esa noche.
Yes.
Sí.
Hold on.
Espera.
Don't just check the Shuiyan House.
No solo revisen la Casa Shuiyan.
Have you ever thought about
¿Alguna vez has pensado en
how Ms. Nie
cómo la Sra. Nie
lost the jade pendant?
perdió el colgante de jade?
About what happened in Xiajiu House,
Sobre lo que pasó en Xiajiu House,
there may be some clues
puede que haya algunas pistas
in the Dragon Gang.
en la Banda Dragón.
Go check it out.
Ve a ver.
Remember
Recuerda
to be careful.
tener cuidado.
Go.
Ve.
Is everything settled?
¿Está todo arreglado?
Your Lordship, don't worry.
Su Señoría, no se preocupe.
I have followed your arrangement
He seguido tu arreglo
and have been against
y he estado en contra
Ning Yuxuan head-on.
ning Yuxuan de frente.
I'm afraid that in the future...
Me temo que en el futuro...
Are you still worried about yourself?
¿Todavía estás preocupada por ti mismo?
If Ning Yuxuan is not eliminated,
Si Ning Yuxuan no se elimina,
do you think
crees que
you can escape?
puedes escapar?
Shen Liancheng
Shen Liancheng
has already settled the matter.
ya ha resuelto el asunto.
Next
Siguiente
it's your turn.
es tu turno.
Got it.
Entiendo.
Let's go to that store.
Vamos a esa tienda.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Coming.
Viniendo.
Sirs.
Señores.
This is your task.
Esta es tu tarea.
This is
Este es
what you need.
lo que necesitas.
Master.
Maestro.
It's done.
Ya está.
Make it quick.
Hazlo rápido.
Ning Yuxuan is really
Ning Yuxuan es realmente
indulged in wishful thinking.
indultado con el deseo.
On the surface,
En la superficie,
he sent his wife to prison
envió a su esposa a la cárcel
to suffer.
sufrir.
In fact, he is protecting her
De hecho, la protege
under his own nose.
bajo su propia nariz.
Don't worry, Master.
No te preocupes, Maestro.
Those we hired
Aquellos que contratamos
are all men of sacrifice
son todos hombres de sacrificio
with the strongest martial arts in Haifang.
con las artes marciales más fuertes en Haifang.
It is said that they are quite professional
Se dice que son bastante profesional
and never fail.
y nunca falle.
With this confession,
Con esta confesión,
the lady with imperial mandate
la dama con mandato imperial
will become a murderer
se convertirá en una asesina
personally taken over by the Court of Judicial Review.
asumido personalmente por el Tribunal de Revisión Judicial.
No matter how powerful Ning Yuxuan is,
No importa lo poderoso que sea ning Yuxuan es,
he can only be sent to the capital
solo puede ser enviado a la capital
with his murderer wife.
con su esposa asesina.
And no one can save him then.
Y nadie lo puede salvar entonces.
Go.
Ir.
What do you want to do?
¿Qué quieres hacer?
Mrs. Ning.
Sra. Ning.
Sorry for that.
Lo siento.
We have never entertained anyone
Nunca hemos entretenido a nadie
of such esteem as you.
de tanta estima como tú.
Forgive us
Perdónanos
for our poor hospitality.
por nuestra pobre hospitalidad.
But
Pero
as long as
en tanto que
you sign the confession,
firmas la confesión,
I will let you down immediately
te dejaré caer inmediatamente
(Confession) and serve you fine food and drink.
(Confesión) y te sirven de comida fina y bebida.
Confession?
¿Confesión?
I didn't kill anyone.
No maté a nadie.
Why should I sign this?
¿Por qué debería firmarlo?
Where is Ning Yuxuan?
¿Dónde está Ning Yuxuan?
Ask him over.
Pregúntale sobre él.
Mr. Ning is handling a case.
El Sr. Ning está manejando un caso.
He sent the two of us over
Envió a los dos de nosotros
to get you to sign.
para que firmes.
(Confess to killing the singsong girl Lianxiang...)
(Confiese en matar la cantautora Lianxiang...)
You don't work for him.
No trabajas para él.
Who sent you over?
¿Quién te envió?
You chose the hard way.
Eligió el camino difícil.
I don't have time
No tengo tiempo
to waste with you.
desperdiciar contigo.
Mrs. Ning.
Sra. Ning.
The soldering iron is just the appetizer.
El hierro soldante es solo el appetizador.
Let me ask you one last time.
Déjame preguntarte una última vez.
Will you sign it or not?
¿Lo firmarás o no?
You rat!
¡Rata!
Nuts!
¡Nueces!
Don't move! Behave yourself!
¡No se mueva! ¡Comportaos!
Take them away.
Llévatlos.
Interrogate them carefully.
Interrogarlos cuidadosamente.
- Yes.
- Sí.
- Go. - Get up.
- Vamos. - Levántate.
Go.
Ve.
Everyone.
Todos.
Thank you for attending
Gracias por asistir
my birthday party today.
mi fiesta de cumpleaños hoy.
I hope you to have fun.
Espero que te diviertas.
Cheers to all.
Bien a todos.
Cheers.
Saludos.
Of course.
Claro.
- Cheers.
- Comentarios.
Please.
Por favor.
More wine.
Más vino.
- Okay. - Great.
- Está bien. - Grande.
More wine for you.
Más vino para ti.
Okay.
Está bien.
Come on.
Vamos.
More wine.
Más vino.
- Okay.
- Está bien.
Sorry, everyone.
Lo siento, todos.
The guzheng has been in disrepair all year round,
El guzheng ha estado en deterioro todo el año,
and the strings were accidentally broken.
y las cuerdas accidentalmente se rompieron.
I'll ask the maid
Voy a pedirle a la criada
to get a new one,
para conseguir una nueva,
and I'll play again for you.
y voy a jugar de nuevo para ti.
Miss Shui.
Señorita Shui.
Today is my birthday,
Hoy es mi cumpleaños,
but you broke the strings to congratulate me.
pero rompiste las cuerdas para felicitarme.
What do you mean?
¿Qué quieres decir?
Are you cursing me to an early death?
¿Me maldices a una muerte temprana?
Mr. Wang, I'm sorry.
Sr. Wang, lo siento.
It's an inadvertent mistake.
Es un error involuntario.
Please forgive me.
Por favor, perdónenme.
Forgive you?
¿Perdón?
Okay.
Está bien.
Drink with me.
Bebe conmigo.
And I will forgive you.
Y te perdonaré.
- Right, come on. - Come on.
- Bien, vamos. - Vamos.
Take this.
Toma esto.
Come on.
Vamos.
Drink with us.
Bebe con nosotros.
This...
Este...
Don't make trouble.
No hagas problemas.
Who are you?
¿Quién eres?
Do you know
¿Sabes
how much I spent on her?
cuánto he gastado en ella?
Mr. Gui, please show mercy.
Sr. Gui, por favor muestre misericordia.
I'm just a singsong girl.
Soy solo una cantina.
Thanks to the appreciation of everyone present,
Gracias a la apreciación de todos los presentes,
I am able to make a living
soy capaz de ganarse la vida
in Haifang.
en Haifang.
Exactly.
Exactamente.
You!
¡Estás bien!
Okay, I won't hurt you.
Está bien, no te haré daño.
I'll drink
Voy a beber
for Miss Shui.
para la señorita Shui.
Are you trying to
¿Estás tratando de
get her out of a fix?
sacarla de una solución?
Then it's not about a glass of wine.
Entonces no se trata de una copa de vino.
- Yes. - Right.
- Sí. - De acuerdo.
- Exactly. - That's it.
- Exacta. - Esa es.
A glass of wine is too easy for you.
Una copa de vino es demasiado fácil para ti.
Indeed.
De hecho.
It's okay.
Está bien.
I am here.
Estoy aquí.
I'm not leaving today.
No me voy hoy.
Leave.
Déjate.
Get out.
Sal.
Be careful.
Ten cuidado.
It's okay if you don't let me in.
Está bien que no me dejes entrar.
I'm at the door anyway.
Estoy en la puerta de todos modos.
I'm not leaving today.
No me voy hoy.
Don't think that after you saved me today,
No crees que después de que me salvaste hoy,
our affairs
nuestros asuntos
will be written off.
se cancelará.
Ji Man.
Ji Man.
I admit that
Admito que
I lied to you.
te mentí.
I hurt you.
Te hice daño.
Sorry.
Lo siento.
Well...
Bueno...
Don't touch me.
No me toques.
Actually
En realidad
I don't know what else I can do.
no sé qué más puedo hacer.
So I just want to be with you
Así que solo quiero estar contigo
and protect you.
y te protege.
Let's suffer in the prison together.
Vamos a sufrir en la cárcel juntos.
In the future...
En el futuro...
If we still have a future,
Si aún tenemos un futuro,
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ Dos corazones se encuentran otra vez amor anunciado ♪
I promise you
Te prometo
whatever compensation you want.
cualquier compensación que quieras.
No matter what happens in the future,
No importa lo que pase en el futuro,
what I want to do now
lo que quiero hacer ahora
is to stand with you
es estar contigo
and find out the person
y descubre a la persona que
who played a trick to frame you.
que jugó un truco para incriminarte.
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ El día que nos vimos por primera vez, el año en que envejecemos ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ Mi corazón y mi amor nunca desaparecerán ♪
♪Summer stars, autumn night♪
♪ estrellas de verano, noche de otoño ♪
♪Who is wandering under the moon in my heart♪
♪ Quién está vagando debajo de la luna en mi corazón ♪
♪The deepest story with the shallowest goodbye♪
♪ La historia más profunda con la más superficial adiós ♪
♪After passing by, I can only meet you in my dream♪
♪ Tras pasar, solo puedo verte en mi sueño ♪
♪The wind can't breeze the long street of time♪
♪ El viento no puede brisa la larga calle de tiempo ♪
♪The burning yearning will never cool♪
♪ El anhelo ardiente nunca se enfriará ♪
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ Dos corazones se encuentran de nuevo el amor anunciado ♪
♪How can I describe it when we look into each other's eyes♪
♪ ¿Cómo lo puedo describir cuando nos fijamos en los ojos del otro ♪
♪Take a life time to write the story♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida para escribir la historia ♪
♪Together with you♪
♪ Junto contigo ♪
♪Company you♪
♪ Compañía contigo ♪
♪Just for your glance and smile♪
♪ Solo por tu mirada y sonrisa ♪
♪The first promise means the forever love♪
♪ La primera promesa significa el amor para siempre ♪
♪Fireworks all over the sky light up your night♪
♪ fuegos artificiales por todo el cielo enciende tu noche ♪
♪Take a life time♪
♪ Tome un tiempo de vida ♪
♪To write the story with you gradually♪
♪ Para escribir la historia contigo gradualmente ♪
♪Just like this♪
♪ Al igual que esto ♪
♪Our love goes on and on♪
♪ Nuestro amor continúa y sigue ♪
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ El día que nos vimos por primera vez, el año en que envejecemos ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ Mi corazón y mi amor nunca desaparecerán ♪